<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on Matthew Haffner</title>
    <link>https://mhaffner.github.io/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordpress on Matthew Haffner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Matthew Haffner</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/wordpress/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Burnination of the Wordpress</title>
      <link>https://mhaffner.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhaffner.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of moving my blog to GitHub pages. I&amp;rsquo;m
doing this for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-ease-of-creating-publishing-posts&#34;&gt;(1) Ease of creating/publishing posts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my first few Wordpress posts I typed content directly in Wordpress.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind this at the time, but eventually I started using Emacs
&lt;code&gt;org-mode&lt;/code&gt; for all writing, including research papers, blog posts,
etc. After a semi-debacle of copying an html-exported &lt;code&gt;org&lt;/code&gt; file into
Wordpress, I never posted again. This manual labor approach did not
appeal to me. I discovered that I could host a blog through GitHub
pages and simply push a &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; file to a repository (much like I was
already doing with code repositories) to create a post. This is much,
much easier than what I was doing with Wordpress before. I&amp;rsquo;m still in
the process of figuring out how to use &lt;code&gt;org-mode&lt;/code&gt; on here, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be
there soon :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-version-control&#34;&gt;(2) Version control&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the unfortunate habit of nuking everying I do pretty regularly,
and git makes me forgive myself exceedingly quicker than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-less-corporate-control-profit-whatever&#34;&gt;(3) Less corporate control/profit/whatever&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more ads. More control for me. No longer do I get sick when I inadvertently
see options to &lt;em&gt;pay&lt;/em&gt; for Wordpress themes thinking about all the innocent people
who have willingly done this (now that I know about Jekyll). &lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: So I
found out that there are plenty of Jekyll themes you can pay for too. But I can
still avoid seeing this easier on GitHub pages. And I have more control this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-easier-to-reflect-changes-to-my-cv&#34;&gt;(4) Easier to reflect changes to my CV&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing wrong with a little self-promotion on a personal blog, right? With
Wordpress I had to upload my new CV through the web interface &lt;em&gt;every time&lt;/em&gt; I
made a change (which is quite often). I&amp;rsquo;m still working on this, but I plan on
creating a symbolic link from my CV repository here, so all I&amp;rsquo;ll have to do is
push the changes to this repository when I update my CV.
&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m now doing this with hard links. Setting it up was pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
